<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Colby Aley</title>
 <link href="http://colbyaley.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://colbyaley.com/"/>
 <updated>2013-06-17T13:25:04-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://colbyaley.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Colby Aley</name>
   <email>colby@aley.me</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Why Most Developers Should Not Be 'Scratching An Itch'</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/scratching-an-itch.html"/>
   <updated>2013-05-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/scratching-an-itch</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you're a developer living in say, San Francisco, making six figures, reading this on a MacBook while sipping tea and pondering startup ideas, I have news for you. You need to throw the popular idea of 'scratching your own itch' out window. It does not and should not apply to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I'm not saying that the idea of scratching an itch is a flawed one. On the contrary, I believe that you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; make something that scratches an itch of yours, that solves a problem you personally have. That's the only way to truly make something great. If you are going to scratch an itch though, please don't scratch the same itch as every other developer. Differentiate yourself. Walk in the shoes of someone who has &lt;strong&gt;actual&lt;/strong&gt; problems that need solving. Consider spending time with people who don't have as much access to technology, what problems do they have? How can you help solve those problems?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developer tools are fun, but there are tons of them. It's a completely over saturated market. Instead of wasting your time on say, another developer tool, open your eyes and make something that changes the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I've recently been thinking about, and it's something other developers, designers, and entrepreneurs should focus on as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>You're not as busy as you think.</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/busy.html"/>
   <updated>2013-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/busy</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&quot;Hey kid, shut the fuck up. You don't know me and you don't know what the hell you're talking about.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that's what is going through your head right now, I invite you to spend three minutes of your life reading this. I guarantee that reading this will not get in the way of your startup raising it's next funding round. It will not stop you from accomplishing your goals. And most importantly, I guarantee you that these three minutes are not what will make or break your success in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People love the idea of being busy. Why? Because it makes them feel important. It makes them feel like someone is relying on them. It makes them feel like they're part of something larger than themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though at the time they may not enjoy it, people naturally like inboxes full of other people depending on them. They like the thought of being busy, shooting emails off like mad, staying up all night coding. Just trying to accomplish their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This occurs in different levels in almost every industry. People who think they are too busy to respond to your call. People who are too important to take a walk and talk with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also happens because people love calculating the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Return_on_investment&quot;&gt;ROI&lt;/a&gt; of everything. People are naturally selfish creatures and love to ask, &quot;what's in it for me?&quot; when presented with a situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans have a problem accepting the fact that sometimes you can't calculate ROI on everything. Some things will not make you any smarter, they will not make you any more successful in your business or personal life, they will not turn you into a millionaire, but that's okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relax a little. Watch that TV show you've always wanted to. Take a walk for no reason at all. Go on that roller coaster once more. Call up your 89 year old grandma on the phone. There are some things that you just have to do that may not make sense in the short term, but in the long term will make all the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember: &lt;a href=&quot;http://jobs.aol.com/articles/2012/02/03/almost-everyone-on-their-death-bed-regrets-working-too-much/&quot;&gt;nobody&lt;/a&gt; ever said on their deathbed, 'I wish I had spent more time working'.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Watching From The Sidelines</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/watching-from-the-sidelines.html"/>
   <updated>2013-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/watching-from-the-sidelines</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's not rare that I stumble upon a blog post where the founder of a startup talks about their launch, how many users they signed up, and how much they learned from it. Well, I think that you can learn a lot from other people's startups too, without having to take part in them. I think the ability to learn from startups that aren't yours is very useful. Here's how I learn from products and the people behind them, all while just watching from the sidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever a new social networking service emerges I usually sign up and try it out, usually to see what the hype is about and to give it a fair chance. I do this because trying out other  apps and services is a great way to learn how to create your own. It's a great chance to learn how they launched and created hype, why people are using it, how effective their signup process is, and most importantly, what aspects of the service you should or should not use in your next project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's a lot you can learn from launches, but if you actually spend some time and use the service, you end up learning a lot more. For as much as the launch exposes about the service and the people behind it, they only undercover a fraction of the methodology behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's important to ask questions such as why are people using it? What real problems does it solve? If there's other services already doing something like this, what makes it special?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's use &lt;a href=&quot;http://foursquare.com&quot;&gt;Foursquare&lt;/a&gt; as an example. Foursquare launched four years ago, but students at my high school are just now beginning to use it. Why now? Why are they using it over Facebook's Places feature, where most students already have accounts? Thanks to the notifications I receive whenever a Facebook friend of mine signs up for Foursquare, I have been able to see exactly how the service is spreading throughout my school. First it was one group of friends, then it spread to another. After becoming Foursquare friends with a few of these people, I was interested to see that many of their checkins have photos attached. From what I've seen, they take many more photos than my original Foursquare friends. Why? Facebook already allows you to attach photos to Places checkins. What makes Foursquare more appealing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is Foursquare targeting these people? From what I can tell, they're using Facebook and Twitter, services the students are already on. Once they can get a few key people to join, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_effect&quot;&gt;network effect&lt;/a&gt; will start doing it's thing, and more and more students will begin to sign up because their friends wanted them to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foursquare aimed at early adopters first, then relied on existing social networks and word of mouth to spread to the average consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foursquare is just one example. I challenge you to sit down and consider how other startups launched, and moved from the early adopter stage to the average consumer stage. What techniques did they use? How did they target the early adopters? Most importantly, how can you apply these techniques to your own startup?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digging below the surface and analyzing products and their launches can be very helpful. There's a lot that you can learn without having to really do anything yourself. What kind of questions will you ponder?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>T-Shirts</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/t-shirts.html"/>
   <updated>2013-03-12T07:25:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/t-shirts</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I find T-Shirts to be fascinating. Give someone a free t-shirt, and unless the content is unnecessairly absurd they will probably wear it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? My guess is that it's because T-Shirts usually cost a fairly substancial amount of money in stores, but branded T-Shirts such as ones with company logos across the front are usually free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've caught myself wearing a T-Shirt before with the logo of a company I don't even care about printed across the front in large bold letters. As far as I know, I've seen other people do it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What fascinates me is that T-Shirts seem to be the only product that we will do this too. Imagine a company giving you a bumber sticker. Unless you truly loved or worked for the company, would you put it on your car? What if they gave you a free T-Shirt, what are the chances that you would wear it at least once?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The List</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/the-list.html"/>
   <updated>2013-01-29T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/the-list</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s what &lt;a href=&quot;http://jacksongariety.com&quot;&gt;Jackson Gariety&lt;/a&gt; and I have been working on for the last few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The List is a social knowledge aggregator, a link sharing site with a focus on high quality content. We’ve identified many of the key problems with other link sharing sites such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; and Reddit, and addressed those with The List.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, one key aspect of The List is that you have to be invited to post, and posting will cost you credits. This forces people to question the quality of the content before they post, which in turn will promote higher quality links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We created The List because we wanted a place to go and find high quality articles related to tech and business. Hopefully you’ll find it helpful as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can apply for an account &lt;a href=&quot;http://thelist.io/apply&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Everyone Should Learn Basic Programming</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/everyone-should-learn-basic-programming.html"/>
   <updated>2013-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/everyone-should-learn-basic-programming</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most common thing I hear from aspiring entrepreneurs is, “I have this idea for an app or site. But I’m not technical, so I need to find someone who can make it for me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great blog post that explains why it is important for everyone, especially entrepreneurs, to learn basic programming. He brings up a great point: If you need to make a site, or make a prototype for your new idea, why rely on someone else? Why not learn how to do it yourself?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What Safety Means for the Future of Computing</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/what-safety-means-for-the-future-of-computing.html"/>
   <updated>2013-01-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/what-safety-means-for-the-future-of-computing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since the inception of the personal computer, using one has been seen as something unhealthy. Something that causes eye strain, carpal tunnel syndrome, and back pains. This has done more than cause trips to the hospital, but has given computers the negative connotations of being unnatural, unsafe, and unhealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computers are becoming more and more present in our every day lives, but at the same time they haven't become any safer to use. More and more jobs involve using computers on a daily basis, yet using one is often seen as unhealthy. In fact, from what I have observed people will naturally limit their computer use because they believe that using one is unnatural and wrong. With something proven to help us in so many ways, why should this still be happening?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we make computers safer to use, and in turn shift in how people use them, and how they are perceived?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the rising number of computers in the home, the workplace, and now in the pocket, this is extremely important. It is something worth thinking about — “What can be done to make computers safer and more natural to use?” I'm not talking about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Trek-TD-01-TrekDesk-Treadmill-Desk/dp/B002IYRBI0&quot;&gt;treadmill desks&lt;/a&gt;. No, I'm talking about designing computers to have less negative health effects, which will in turn fundamentally alter how people think of, and use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's a huge opportunity for the first person to figure this out, and an even larger one for the first person to do it right.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why I Still Use A Radio</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/why-i-still-use-a-radio.html"/>
   <updated>2012-12-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/why-i-still-use-a-radio</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;About a year ago I bought a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tivoliaudio.com/&quot;&gt;Tivoli Audio&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tivoliaudio.com/products/table-radios/model-one-reg-radio-in-classic-walnut-beige.html&quot;&gt;Model One&lt;/a&gt; radio to play in my bedroom/office as background music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already know what you’re asking, “A radio? Why?” Sure, I could have plugged my iPhone into a pair of speakers and played Pandora, Rdio, or my personal iTunes collection. Sure that gets the music playing, but it also adds clutter and complicates things. Instead of simply being able to enjoy the music, I would be faced with more problems, such as not being able to use my phone while the music is playing. Also, I’ve found that having to select my own music is a huge distraction. Sure these problems may seem small, but let me tell you, they noticiably affect my music listening habbits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://aley.media.s3.amazonaws.com/DSC_50001.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700px&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tivoli has three knobs. No screen, no buttons, no internet. Is that a downside? I don’t think so. Sometimes the simplest solution is the best, even if it means paying for &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; product. The Tivoli does one thing, and it does it well. It plays AM/FM radio with excellent sound quality and reception. It is a standalone product, manufactured to preform one specific task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But don’t you want to listen to your own music?” No, not really. Sure I listen to my own music when I’m out and about, on my way to school or running errands. I have my radio on almost 24/7 in my bedroom as background music. I listen to it when I do schoolwork, sleep, you name it. There’s a great local jazz station that I listen to, and I hardly ever change it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it helps to take a step back from our complicated gadgets and find a product that solves one specific problem. A product that you don’t have to worry about, that you can use for weeks on end without touching a single time. Sometimes simplifying things means owning multiple devices that overlap in functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just want to have music playing in the background without having to worry about it. That’s what a Radio is for, and that’s why I still use one.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Startups And Success</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/startups-and-success.html"/>
   <updated>2012-12-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/startups-and-success</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Success in the startup world is too narrowly defined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you ask your neighbor to list three successful startups, they will probably list something along the lines of Twitter, Facebook, and Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure these companies have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/10/04/facebook-1-billion-users_n_1938675.html&quot;&gt;users out the wazoo&lt;/a&gt;, do you have to as well? No. Yeah, you can be successful by gaining millions of users, but success is much more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Success in the world of startups is making a profitable company. It’s solving the problem that your customer has, even if that customer isn’t everyone and their brother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to focus on solving the problems of 100% of the world’s population. Instead, solve the problem that 2% of the world has, and do it well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://37signals.com&quot;&gt;37Signals&lt;/a&gt;, a startup often regarded as successful. They aren’t used by everyone you know. Instead, they found a niche and served that niche well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all startups are as sexy as you see on &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com&quot;&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;. Don’t do a startup with your only goal being to become rich and famous. Instead, make a kickass product that’s profitable and solves the problem that your customer has.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How I Use Simplenote</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/simplenote.html"/>
   <updated>2012-08-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/simplenote</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I discovered &lt;a href=&quot;http://simplenoteapp.com/&quot;&gt;Simplenote&lt;/a&gt; quite some time ago through a podcast I listen to, but have just recently decided to try it out. If you are unaware of what Simplenote is, it’s a freemium service that allows you to sync notes, essentially .txt files, easily across your Mac, PC, and iOS device using 1st and &lt;a href=&quot;http://simplenoteapp.com/downloads/&quot;&gt;3rd party apps&lt;/a&gt;. Since signing up I’ve been paying for the $2/month &lt;a href=&quot;http://simplenoteapp.com/premium/&quot;&gt;premium plan&lt;/a&gt; that comes with a couple extra features as well as premium support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use Simplenote pretty much as a braindump. The files in my Simplenote are somewhat unorganized. The main file is a my todo list, where I simply jot down all the things I have to do that I probably would not remember without the list. My Simplenote is also full of business ideas, books to read, fonts I like, blog posts (like this one) and websites that I think are well designed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use a couple different Simplenote apps. Justnotes on the Mac and Listary as well as the official app on the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justnotes [&lt;a href=&quot;http://selfcoded.com/justnotes/&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Justnotes is one of the most simple and beautiful Mac apps that I’ve used. It integrates seamlessly with Simplenote and can also back up to your Mac’s local drive. I keep it open whenever I’m on my mac and use it to keep track of everything; code, todo lists, books to read, movies to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listary [&lt;a href=&quot;http://listaryapp.com/&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Listary is a great iOS app for keeping lists and syncing them with Simplenote. I use it when I’m on the go and need to add something to my todo list, or hear of a book that I’d like to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simplenote is one of those services that just works. You don’t have to think about it, you just use it. I recommend that you try it… the free version is great and the paid version is always there if you find that you crave more.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why Twitter No Longer Cares About Developers</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/why-twitter-doesnt-care-about-developers.html"/>
   <updated>2012-08-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/why-twitter-doesnt-care-about-developers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, Twitter has released multiple blog posts &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marco.org/2012/08/16/twitter-api-changes&quot;&gt;pretty much&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.twitter.com/blog/changes-coming-to-twitter-api&quot;&gt;stating&lt;/a&gt; that they are no longer interested in people developing applications for their platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter has decided to turn its back against 3rd party app developers because of monetization. After taking millions in VC funding, Twitter finally has to start showing some real numbers to those investors. So they’ve decided to do away with the ecosystem of 3rd party clients. Many people have been asking, “why doesn’t Twitter just require developers to put Twitter’s ads in their software?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would not work for a couple of reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter’s revenue can’t rely on 3rd parties. As an example, what happens if &lt;a href=&quot;http://tapbots.com/software/tweetbot/&quot;&gt;Tweetbot&lt;/a&gt; brings in 5% of Twitter’s annual revenue, then the guys at Tapbots decide to close doors? Twitter’s investors would not be happy. No venture-backed company in their right mind would rely on 3rd parties for revenue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with developers to incorporate ads would be extremely cumbersome. Twitter’s ecosystem includes 1 million apps &lt;a href=&quot;http://mashable.com/2011/07/11/twitter-1-million-applications/&quot;&gt;as of&lt;/a&gt; last year. How do you expect Twitter to reach out to all of them? Easy. You only reach out to the top few. Sure, that will work until users flock (see what I did there?) to less popular apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;These new updates make it clear that Twitter has focused on making their investors happy rather than their developers, and inevitably their millions of users. Do they have a reason to? Sure. Is it the best option for the users? Probably not.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Young Entrepreneurs Business Week 2012</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/yebw-2012.html"/>
   <updated>2012-07-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/yebw-2012</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After hearing about it through a friend from school, I decided to sign up for Oregon’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://yebw.org&quot;&gt;Young Entrepreneurs Business Week&lt;/a&gt; at Oregon State University. YEBW is a week-long event / camp for high school students to learn about business and entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students come from around the country, from as close as five minutes away to as far as the state of New York. Students are separated into companies / groups that contain about 10 students and one mentor, who are men and women that come from companies around Oregon. In these companies students are assigned roles such as CEO, CMO, etc. Throughout the week, students in their companies learn how to run a business using the “BIZSim” program, and learn how to form a business with various activities. YEBW also strives to teach participants’ networking skills with various social gatherings such as movies and games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout my experience at YEBW I kept a nightly log of what I learned during the day and any observations that I made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 1 − 7/15/12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got settled in the dorms and whatnot. The campus is extremely quiet and at any given moment I could probably find more bikes than cars. Awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are about 150 kids, but I really wonder why some of them are here. I love it when people can prove that experience means nothing, so in a way it’s cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little birdie tells me that some students are here because of a program that pays them to attend. I’m not a fan as it really dilutes the group of passionate students with kids who aren’t the least bit interested. The best is when the students themselves decide to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group of company advisors / mentors looks awesome and they all come from different industries. Mine works in finance at Boeing. Rad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve started working on BIZSim, the business simulation program. I’ve noticed that the companies you run with BIZSim are total brick and mortar companies that have to worry about inventory and supply. That’s something I didn’t know about before, so it’s neat to learn about something completely new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently nobody on this campus has discovered what air conditioners are, because I’ve yet to visit a building that has one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 2 − 7/16/12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We toured the OSU College of Business as well as listened to a talk about the College of Engineering by an engineering professor. It’s obvious why OSU is interested in backing YEBW as you are taught about the university quite a bit in hopes that you will consider applying when the time comes. As my mother is a University of Oregon alum (OSU rival), I’m pretty biased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The engineering professor was awesome. To start, he rode in on a Segway to explain how it’s an engineering marvel. I still think he was just running a bit too late to walk. He claimed to have had the idea for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.javajacket.com/&quot;&gt;JavaJacket&lt;/a&gt;, which according to him was stolen by the Starbucks employees who he shared it with. I actually believe him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight we listened to an hour-long motivational speech by a person named &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/pages/Life-Happens-Live-It/&quot;&gt;Jake French&lt;/a&gt; who faced a spinal cord injury in 2008 and was confined to a wheelchair, not being able to move neither his arms nor his legs. He shared with us some inspiring stories, such as how his accident taught him a lot about himself, even though it felt as if he was “sent back to square one” in life. The speech was great though I question how fitting it really was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, I was appointed to Chief Operating Officer in my BIZSim company. I found that quite funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 3 − 7/17/12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we listened to a plethora of inspirational speakers. Their talks were, for the most part, very inspiring and uplifting. We listened to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ZekeCamusio&quot;&gt;Zeke Camusio&lt;/a&gt;, who discussed the many failures and successes throughout his life as an entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also heard from &lt;a href=&quot;http://louradja.com/&quot;&gt;Lou Radja&lt;/a&gt;, who talked about helping others once you become successful. His speech was extremely interesting and memorable. You could tell that he practiced and that he custom tailored the speech to fit out event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third person who spoke to us was &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/clivecoffee&quot;&gt;Mark&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://clivecoffee.com&quot;&gt;Clive Coffee&lt;/a&gt;, who spoke to us about his company and how he manages it, as well as the new product he is working on now. The guy seems to know a lot about marketing, which is awesome because as we all know, marketers rule the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we listened to a speech about discrimination. As you could imagine, it wasn’t really anything new but rather an extremely enthusiastic speaker going into fine detail about different types of discrimination. To be honest I am not completely sure how it fit into the YEBW theme of business. &lt;em&gt;Yes, I do understand that it is important to not discriminate as an employer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 4 − 7/18/12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all listened to a talk titled “Death by PowerPoint” that points out the characteristics of both good and bad presentations. This will help us tomorrow when we start working on two presentations that we will have to give on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 5 − 7/19/12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today my company / group stayed up until 11:30 PM creating two presentations that we will give tomorrow to a panel of judges. I had the idea of opening with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wvsboPUjrGc&quot;&gt;Steve Ballmer inspired&lt;/a&gt; “I LOVE THIS COMPANY,” but the idea got shot down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our practice time was interrupted by a presentation about personal finance. The presentation was informational and actually pretty interesting, even though it took up an hour of our precious time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After catching up on news and practicing my speech, I didn’t end up getting any sleep until nearly 2 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 6 − 7/20/12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Woke up at 5:45 AM stressed out about these presentations. For you mathematicians, yes, that equates to 3.75 hours of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the day my group gave our two presentations to the judges. We received some great feedback, and the presentations went very well considering how much we practiced them (not much).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learned the next day that we actually won one of our presentations, meaning that we did better than any other group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our last dinner here, we ate a formal meal where we were taught some important etiquette rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also a dance. Takeaway: Nobody here knows how to dance, including me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YEBW was an unforgettable experience. Going back home will be extremely bittersweet. I hope to be able to return next year since they have different curriculum for second and third year students. I got a chance to meet some awesome people in the community, as well as learn more about business and marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would definitely suggest it to anyone interested in business or entrepreneurship. It’s truly a great opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Guest Post: How to Converse Fluently on Twitter</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/conversing-on-twitter.html"/>
   <updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/conversing-on-twitter</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;WePost Media is a internet marketing and social media consulting company based out of here in Portland. I recently wrote a guest post for their blog detailing the multiple ways to converse and communicate on Twitter. I’ve found that quite a few people still don’t know exactly how @replies work, so I tried to clear up some confusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wepostmedia.com/parlez-vous-twitterese-or-how-to-converse-fluently-on-twitter/&quot;&gt;read the post over at the WePost Media blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Five Most Annoying Buzzwords</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/buzzwords.html"/>
   <updated>2012-07-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/buzzwords</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Buzzwords are everywhere. Words that have little meaning and value, used only to make a product sound more enticing and cutting edge. In reality, using buzzwords just makes you sound like an idiot. Sometimes these words can have legitimate meanings, but it’s the large amount of people applying random meanings to them that gives the word buzzword status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though there are (way too) many buzzwords flying around to list them all, here’s five that annoy me the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The ‘Cloud’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Let’s just admit it, nobody knows what “the cloud” really is. In reality, the word is nothing more than a cute name for servers that belong to other people. The cloud doesn’t consist of fairies and unicorns, but rather ugly old servers with huge hard drives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The ‘App’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Ever since the Apple App Store launched, apps have been hotter than ever. Consumers love their apps, so companies assume that they want apps everywhere. On their TV, in their car, on their wrist, even on the refrigerator. Though apps are real things, it’s the marketing departments that overuse the word, giving it buzzword status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. ‘Innovative’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
So your idea is innovative? Whoa! Finally, someone who has an innovative idea! Jokes aside, I hate this word. Don’t tell people that your idea is innovative, prove it to them. Let them be the judge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. ‘Disrupt’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
People use this word far too often in startup pitches. It drives me nuts. It makes you sound like an idiot and your idea sound goofy. That’s not what you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. ‘x for y’ analogies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
It’s Instagram for video! Twitter for cats. Foursquare for pilots. Facebook for toddlers… Argh! These drive me bonkers. Riding the wave of other people’s success is dangerous, and that’s exactly what this is. Don’t do it, kids.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A 15 Year-Old&#8217;s Startup Weekend Experience</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/a-15-year-olds-startup-weekend-experience.html"/>
   <updated>2012-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/a-15-year-olds-startup-weekend-experience</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I walked in to Startup Weekend a week ago I had absolutely no experience at all. I did not know how to code a website, to develop an app, to create a logo, or how to start a business. I was nothing more than an inexperienced 15 year old with a desire to create something cool and learn a bit while doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had spent the previous three days creating and practicing my one minute elevator pitch. I was ninth in line, and close to 70 people would be pitching after me. Before I knew it I was speaking in front of 150 strangers, including some of Portland’s most successful entrepreneurs, designers, and developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After giving my pitch and listening to the pitches of everyone else, it was finally time to vote on the ideas. Some of the ideas got no votes, while some of the ideas received up to 26 votes. After being tallied up by the organizers, it was announced that my idea had received 11 votes, enough to make it to the top 15 ideas. These top 15 ideas would then attract teams of Startup Weekend attendees and be developed over the course of the weekend. I formed a team with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/kwestin&quot;&gt;Ken Westin&lt;/a&gt;, who I had known before the weekend, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/joeypetelle&quot;&gt;Joey Petelle&lt;/a&gt;, an extremely smart person. We would spend the next 50 hours working on &lt;a href=&quot;http://uEdit.me&quot;&gt;uEdit.me&lt;/a&gt;, a service that connects writers and bloggers with editors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned more over the course of that weekend than any textbook or schoolteacher could teach me in a year. I learned what goes in to creating a business, how to work well in a small group of people, and how to determine what needs to get done in order to meet the deadline. I walked in to &lt;a href=&quot;http://portland.startupweekend.org&quot;&gt;Portland Startup Weekend&lt;/a&gt; with no experience whatsoever, and still found a way to get as much out of it as I had expected. What &lt;a href=&quot;http://startupweekend.org/&quot;&gt;they say&lt;/a&gt; is true, Startup Weekend is a no talk, all action environment. You are not judged based on your experience, but on how well you can get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startup Weekend was an extraordinary experience, and was an invaluable use of my time and money. I learned a lot and met some of Portland’s greatest entrepreneurs. My team and I have decided to move on with our project, uEdit.me, and are making great strides towards a version accessible to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would encourage anyone to &lt;a href=&quot;http://startupweekend.org&quot;&gt;attend a Startup Weekend&lt;/a&gt;. Whether you work for a Fortune 500 company, are unemployed, or anywhere in-between, there’s certainty something you could learn from attending a Startup Weekend event. At Startup Weekend qualifications do not matter, it’s what you do during the weekend that counts.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Best iPhone Case Is No Case At All</title>
   <link href="http://colbyaley.com/the-best-iphone-case-is-no-case-at-all.html"/>
   <updated>2012-04-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://colbyaley.com/the-best-iphone-case-is-no-case-at-all</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since I purchased my first iPhone, a 16GB iPhone 3G, I’ve used a case. I’ve tried out some great cases, like the Speck CandyShell, Speck PixelSkin HD, and the Twelve South BookBook. I’ve also used some not so great cases such as the Apple iPhone Bumper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a week ago I took my iPhone out of the case to dust off the back of it as well as clean the screen. I then realized what a beautiful device the iPhone is and how light it is without a case. Why would I want to cover up such a beautiful device? I decided that for the rest of the day I would not use a case. As the day went on I questioned why I ever put a case on the beautiful iPhone to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without the case I was a little afraid that the phone would break if I dropped it, but to this date that has not happened. I have found that I rarely drop my iPhone, so this really isn’t a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you keep a case on your phone, why? I haven’t looked back since taking the case off of my iPhone. The phone is lighter, feels better in the hand, and looks better. If you currently have a case on your phone, I challenge you to take the case off for a day.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>